BENJAMIN GAMBLING

#: +1 604-905-9464

Email: benjamin.gambling@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/benjamin-gambling Portfolio: https://benjamin-gambling.github.io/

PROFILE

I'm a self-taught full-stack web developer with a professional history in computational structural dynamics and guest experience. Specializing in JavaScript I have developed a strong portfolio of responsive and visually pleasing web applications using modern technologies, test driven development and object orientated design, all with a focus on writing clean, elegant and efficient code

EDUCATION

2020 THE ODIN PROJECT BOOCAMP

Working through a structured online bootcamp that's focused on Full Stack Web Development in both JavaScript and Ruby on Rails. Along side other online resources such as Harvard CS50 and the Free Code Camp, I have created a number of personal projects and coursework. Aligning their curriculums help me gain a deeper understanding of web development concepts and helped reinforce the subjects I had learnt.

2010-2014 UNIVERSITY OF SHEFFIELD - MENG CIVIL & STRUCTURAL ENGINEERING

Specializing in structural dynamics in high stress situations, mainly high-rise structures under blast, fire and seismic loads. My final year project involved modelling steel framed structures under high temperature loadings. Receiving a final grade of 2:1 with honours.

EXPERIENCE

CURRENT BENJAMIN GAMBLING WEB DEVELOPMENT - FREELANCER

Through my Web Development education I worked part time freelancing through websites like Upwork and <u>freelancing.com</u>, mainly doing front end projects aswell as some minor backend work. I also offered pro bono work to friends and my local community during COVID-19, helping improve their online presence aswell as giving them my advice.

WEATHER TODO - LEAD DEVELOPER

Currently working in my spare time creating an app that helps people plan their lives around the constantly changing weather. Instead of having separate apps where you have to constantly search the weather for a number of different places to plan your whole life, this wraps it all into one making ti clear what you are doing and what you need to take, depending on the weather. It is designed using React with Apollo and GraphQL with the OpenWeatherMap API. It will first be able as a Web App before using React Native to create an IOS and Android version.

2016 - 2020 VAIL RESORTS - SUPERVISOR, PRODUCT SALES & SERVICES

Working in number of roles leading large teams of seasonal employees who are required to sell products and provide exceptional guest service. During my time I have played an instrumental part in the testing and integration of a new point of sales system, which was produced in house and is continuously being developed.

2014 - 2016 TPS CONSULT - STRUCTURAL ENGINEER

The role consisted of a range of different roles such blast engineering, structural analysis and design, counter terrorism measures , hostile vehicle mitigation and explosive safety. I also was invalided with the structural engineering team where I developed some tools and strategies to create efficient pad foundation design.

LANGUAGES / FRAMEWORKS

Front-End

- JavaScript (ES6 +)
- TypeScript
- HTML5
- CSS3/SASS
- React
- Bootstrap
- Webpack
- D3
- Apollo Client

Back-End

- Node
- Express
- Prisma
- Apollo Server
- GraphQL
- Ruby

SQL/NoSQL

- PresgreSQL/SQLite
- MongoDB

Test Driven Development

- Jest/Jasmine

Cloud Platforms

- Heroku
- Firebase

Version Control

- Git
- Github

SKILLS

- Problem solving
- Critical thinking
- Object-orientated design
- Working with modern technologies
- Leadership/Teamwork
- Adaptability